Guide to the Samuel I. Katz papers, 1937-1993 MS0516.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Samuel I. Katz papers
1937-1993
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Katz, Samuel Irving
MS0516.UA
0.5 Linear Feet
Samuel I. Katz received his B.A. degree from GW in 1940 and his M.A. degree in 1942. Materials in this collection include correspondence, a birth certificate, resume, statistical reports by Samuel Katz papers, a scrapbook and an obituary, biography, U.S. Forces European Theater Certificate. The collection cover the years 1937 through 1993.
Box 1
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Provenance of this collection is unknown.
Biographical Note
Samuel I. Katz received his B.A. degree from GW in 1940 and his M.A. degree in 1942.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include correspondence, a birth certificate, resume, statistical reports by Samuel Katz papers, a scrapbook and an obituary, biography, U.S. Forces European Theater Certificate. The collection cover the years 1937 through 1993.
World War, 1939-1945; Reports and dissertations; Biography; Washington (D.C.); Scrapbooks; George Washington University; Katz, Samuel Irving; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae
- Letters From Europe, 1957-58, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General note
  Bound edition of collected letters
- Samuel Irving Katz, Department of State Passport, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.1)
- In Celebration of the Life Of Samuel Katz - luncheon program, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.2)
- Certificate of Birth, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.3)
- Professional Resume, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.4)
- Application to London School of Economics, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2.5)
- Official Travel, undated (Box 1, Folder 2.6)
- International Adjustment and Finance: Lessons, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2.7)
  Published in an Economic Journal, 21(1)
- Remarks at the Cosmos Club, by Shuja Nawaz, 10/21/1993 (Box 1, Folder 2.8)
  About Sam Katz as Editor of Finance & Development
- London School of Economics and Political Science. Course 226: Economic History From 1815, Part I. Syllabus, undated (Box 1, Folder 3.1)
- Samuel Katz Economics Problem, 10/19/1937 (Box 1, Folder 3.2)
- Statistical Report of the United States Deciduous Fruit Export Season, 1938-39 -- United States Department of Agricultural, Office of Foreign Argicultural Relations, 12/1939 (Box 1, Folder 3.3)
- Statistical Report of the United States Deciduous Fruit Export Season, 1937-38 -- United States Department of Agricultural, Office of Foreign Argicultural Relations, 03/1939 (Box 1, Folder 3.4)
- Harrod's Theory of the Trade Cycle - a review, 05/21/1941 (Box 1, Folder 3.5)
  2 copies. One with comments and one without
- The Savings Dilemma, 01/1939 (Box 1, Folder 3.6)
- Finance Development- In Memoriam Samuel I. Katz (1916-1993), undated (Box 1, Folder 4.1)
- Obituaries, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.2)
- Letter from Brian Rose, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.3)
- Life Bio sent by Federal Reserve Board, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.4)
- Memorial Service Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.5)
- Churchill Club membership, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.6)
- Registration Certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.7)
- US Forces European Theatre Certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.8)
- Correspondence, speeches, general notices from U.S. Army, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.9)
- Rockefeller Public Service Awards program, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.1)
- Publications listings, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.11)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.12)
- Course Description, undated (Box 1, Folder 4.13)